<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on John Newbery</title>
    <link>https://johnnewbery.com/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on John Newbery</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 22 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://johnnewbery.com/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Building a Stronger Bitcoin Developer Community</title>
      <link>https://johnnewbery.com/post/building-a-stronger-bitcoin-developer-community/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Oct 2017 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://johnnewbery.com/post/building-a-stronger-bitcoin-developer-community/</guid>
      <description>(originally posted at https://medium.com/@jfnewbery/)
In Summer 2016, I’d been interested in Bitcoin for a little over a year. I’d been slowly becoming more and more enchanted by this strange and wonderful technology, and I’d finally made the step of quitting my job of eight years with the intention of finding a way to make a living by working on Bitcoin. Matt Corallo’s announcement of the first Hacker Residency was very happy timing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An Introduction to Bitcoin Core Fee Estimation</title>
      <link>https://johnnewbery.com/post/an-intro-to-bitcoin-core-fee-estimation/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Sep 2017 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://johnnewbery.com/post/an-intro-to-bitcoin-core-fee-estimation/</guid>
      <description>(originally posted at https://bitcointechtalk.com/)
Why we have fees Space in the Bitcoin blockchain is a limited resource, and given a low enough price, demand for that space will far exceed the supply. If block space is free, people will find all kinds of uses for it — decentralised gambling, uploading an entire copy of the Bitcoin whitepaper, and timestamping individual documents are just a few examples we’ve seen in the past.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contributing to Bitcoin Core, a Personal Account</title>
      <link>https://johnnewbery.com/post/contributing-to-bitcoin-core-a-personal-account/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Aug 2017 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://johnnewbery.com/post/contributing-to-bitcoin-core-a-personal-account/</guid>
      <description>In January of this year, I moved to New York to take a job contributing full time to open source Bitcoin projects. These are some of my experiences in those first few months.
First of all, I recognize that I’m incredibly fortunate. Not only do I have tremendous freedom to work on what I think is important or interesting, I get to sit alongside and work directly with brilliantly talented and motivated people.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>